Guide to the Thomas Jefferson Jackson See Papers, 1891-1970
Department of Special Collections
Thomas Jefferson Jackson See Papers,
1891-1970
Special Collections M0218
See, T.J.J.
1.5 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Provenance
Transfer from Memorial Auditorium Storage
Biography
Thomas Jefferson Jackson See, born 19 February 1866 in Missouri, was an astronomer and mathematician who established laws of the Formation of the Solar System and founded the science of cosmogony.
Scope and Content
Summary: Consists of original drafts and copies of scientific papers written by T. J. J. See. Also included are miscellaneous items reflective of his career.
Container List
- n.d.10th Paper- "New Theory of the Aether" by T.J.J. See, original manuscript, legal size (Box 1, Folder 1)
- 1928, Augustcarbon copy (4th) of the above. (Box 1, Folder 2)
- 1930, May 2411th Paper "New Theory of the Aether" by T.J.J. See - Original manuscript (Box 1, Folder 3)
- n.d.Same as 1-3, 1st typed copy (Box 2, Folder 1)
- n.d.Same as 1-3, Carbon (Box 2, Folder 2)
- n.d.Same as 1-3, Carbon (Box 2, Folder 3)
- 193012th Paper - "New Theory of the Aether", original manuscript (Box 2, Folder 4)
- n.d.Same as 2-5, 1st typed copy (Box 2, Folder 5)
- n.d.Same as 2-5, 3rd typed copy (Box 2, Folder 6)
- n.d.Same as 2-5, 4th typed copy (Box 2, Folder 7)
- n.d."Research in Transcendental Geometry and the Theory of Infinite Space." original manuscript (Box 3, Folder 1)
- n.d.Same as 3-1, Typed copy, chaps. 1-8 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- n.d.Same as 3-1, Typed copy, chaps. 9-14, 18 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- 1926, Nov 8"Dynamical Theory of the Rotations of the Planets and the Direct and Retrograde Motions of Their Satellites, with Especial Reference to the Untenable Doctrine of Planetary Inversion" by T.J.J. See, 3rd carbon copy. (Box 3, Folder 4)
- (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - a) Lowell Observatory Accounts - T.J.J. See - red leatherbound notebook 1897, July 1
  - b) A. Pen and pencil accounts, 8 vo, 4 to, and legal, typed. n.d.
  - c) 2 recepits for freight on Pacific Express Co. 1898, Aug 8
  - d) 2 pgs. pencil budget n.d.
- (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - a) 2 printed posters announcing conferral of PhD honoris causa to T.J.J. See, Otto Hirschfeld and Rudolf Virchow. n.d.
  - b) als C.M.H. Hawley to T.J.J. See 1904, July 14
  - c) als Maheon S. Tisdale to T.J.J. See re: birthday congratulations 1961, Feb. 24
  - d) Edward A. Beach to T.J.J. See on White House Stationery-xerox 1954, Dec 1
  - e) als T.J.J. See to American Philosophical Society re: laws of nature 1964, Oct 20
  - f) same as 3-6e, 19 photocopies
  - g) Announcement of a great discovery... printed article with notations by T.J.J. See with BW portrait [See?]
  - h) General Summary on Forces of Nature by T.J.J. See. 26 xerox copies. 1960, Oct 1
  - i) A. Outline of Last Will and Testament, T.J.J. See. n.d.
  - j) Typed statement on the Relations between T.J.J. See and Ormond Stone